Guide to the General Collection Manuscript Music Miscellany
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Honegger, Arthur, 1892-1955
  - Music
    - Jeanne d'Arc au bûcher. Vocal score
      - "Jeanne d'Arc au bûcher / Arthur Honegger; poème de Paul Claudel", [1939?]; 1 score (141 p.); 33 cm. (Box Volume 44)
        Printed vocal score (Paris: Editions Maurice Senart, c1939), with manuscript annotations, possibly by Ida Rubinstein.
        Unnumbered example from 500 copies with woodcut by Louis-Joseph Soulas.
        Stamp on cover: Editions Salabert.
        Plate number: E.M.S. 8819 (Editions Maurice Senart).
        Card with manuscript notes laid in.
        Ex libris René Berthelot.
    - Judith
      Opera, with libretto by René Morax.
      Composed 1925; first performed 1926.
      Former group number: 37 HONEGGER, ARTHUR
      - Title page from Judith, 1928 Jan 30; 1 item (1 p.); 19 cm. (Box Folder 291)
        Title page with dedication to Madam Marsan, holograph, signed.
- Hugo, Valentine, 1887-1968
  - Other Papers
    - Notes and commentary on music, 1959-60; 4 items. (Box Folder 292)
      AMS, with corrections in the hand of the author, entitled "Ici New York," and three additional manuscript notes concerning music. With mimeographed invitation to a press conference held by Pierre Schaeffer, dated 1960, Apr 12, with an ANS response from Hugo written at top of invitation, and "envoye message" above ANS.
      Former group number: 38 HUGO, VALENTINE
      Purchased from Claude Oterelo on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 1995.
  - Restricted Fragile
    - Folder 292, 1959-60; 2 items. (Box Restricted Fragile Folder 8)
- Indy, Vincent d', 1851-1931
  - Correspondence
    - Fuchs, Madame, 1887 Jan 1; 1 item (2 p.); 15 cm. (Box Folder 293)
      ALS to Fuchs, Paris, concerning a rehearsal and referring to Johannes Brahms.
      Former group number: 39 INDY, VINCENT D'
      Purchased from Lisa Cox (Sotheby's, 2000 May 26, lot 212) on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund.
    - Hartog, Eduard de, 1902 December 3; 1 item (3 p.). (Box Folder 408)
      Autograph letter, signed, about Isidore De Lara.
      Accompanied by a typed transcript made by a former owner.
      Purchased from L'Autographe S. A. on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2004.
    - Kufferath, M. (Maurice), 1897 April-May; 2 items. (Box Folder 405)
      2 autograph letters, signed, in response to criticism of the Scola Cantorum by Trotot-Deriot in the Guide musical.
      Accompanied by partial typed transcripts made by a former owner.
    - Monfort, 1902 Sep 23; 1 item (2 p.); 18 cm. (Box Folder 294)
      ALS to "Mon cher Monfort,"concerning composition lessons.
    - Monteux, Pierre, 1929 April 11; 1 item (1 postcard). (Box Folder 452)
      Autograph letter, signed, expressing gratitude to Monteux and Alfred Cortot, and referring to a symphony by d'Indy.
      On verso: photograph of d'Indy by Frantisek Drtikol, Prague, 1925.
      Purchased from Bernard Quaritch (Sotheby's London sale, 2001 December 7, lot 69) on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2002.
    - Philipp, Isidore, 1888 April 28; 1 item (2 p.). (Box Folder 407)
      Autograph letter, signed, with address leaf, asking permission to dedicate his Petite sonate pour piano dans la forme classique, op. 9, to Philipp.
    - Ravel, Maurice, 1899 Apr 29; 1 item (2 p.); 18 cm. (Box Folder 295)
      ALS concerning a work by Ravel to be conducted by d'Indy.
    - Reyer, Ernest, [circa 1877]; 1 item (2 p.). (Box Folder 402)
      Autograph letter, signed, about d'Indy's Antoine et Cléopatre overture.
    - Samazeuilh, Gustave, [1899]-1917; 12 items. (Box Folder 398)
      2 autograph letters, signed, to Samazeuilh, and 10 autograph letters, signed, to unidentified recipients, most to "mon cher ami" or "chère Madame." Letters to Samazeuilh concern appointments; other letters include discussion of music performances and d'Indy's views on music education.
    - Samazeuilh, Gustave, 1890-1930, undated; 24 items. (Box Folder 399)
      24 autograph letters, signed, some with envelopes, about d'Indy's music and conducting, referring to Edouard Colonne, d'Indy's opera Fervaal, and composition of symphonies.
    - Schneklud, Fritz, 1890 April 9; 1 item (3 p.). (Box Folder 409)
      Autograph letter, signed, referring to the Fondation Beethoven and to concerts by Schneklud.
      Purchased from Les Autographes on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2004.
    - Veluard, Antoinette, [1908]-[1910?]; 3 items. (Box Folder 401)
      2 autograph letters, signed: on a postcard with image of d'Indy's home, Les Faugs, Ardèche, expressing thanks, with an unidentified music quotation; and about travel plans, possibly to Belgium. With a postcard photograph of d'Indy.
    - Unidentified, 1916 August 9; 1 item (4 p.). (Box Folder 397)
      Autograph letter, signed, to "mon cher Monfort," about Italian madrigals.
    - Unidentified, 1912 July 5; 1 item (2 p.). (Box Folder 400)
      Autograph letter, signed,to "Monsieur," about composition of d'Indy's opera La lègende de Saint Christophe.
    - Unidentified, no year July 13; 1 item (3 p.). (Box Folder 403)
      Autograph letter, signed, to "cher Monsieur," about efforts to arrange performance of an opera by d'Indy, and mentioning Firmin Gémier and the Odéon theater.
      Purchased from Jean-Jacques Faure on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2003.
    - Unidentified, 1917 November 4; 1 item (2 p.). (Box Folder 404)
      Autograph letter, signed, to "chère Madamoiselle," declining to assist with a request.
    - Unidentified, 1897 January-February; 3 items. (Box Folder 406)
      3 autograph letters, signed, to "cher Monsieur," director of the Théâtre des Beaux-Arts, Brussels, recommending Octave Maus for the croix de Chevalier de la Légion d'Honneur, and Léon Van Hout for the ruban d'officier d'Académie.
      Accompanied by typed transcripts made by a former owner.
    - Unidentified, 1921 August [19?]; 1 item (2 p.). (Box Folder 410)
      Autograph letter, signed, to "Monsieur," declining to set a poem sent by his correspondent to music.
      Purchased from A Saint-Benoit-des-prés on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2004.
- Inghelbrecht, D. E. (Désiré Emile), 1880-1965
  - Music
    - Songs. Selections
      4 chansons populaires françaises: originally for unaccompanied chorus. Composed 1915; published 1925.
      La légende du grand Saint Nicolas: for voice and orchestra. Published 1932.
      - Songs with orchestra, 1932-1934; 1 v. of music (23, 13, 16, 16, 13 p.); 33 cm. (Box Volume 45)
        Printed proof score for La légende du grand Saint Nicolas (Paris: Rouart Lerolle, c1932), with manuscript corrections. Bound with 4 chansons populaires françaises, arranged for solo voice and orchestra, holograph score, each song dated at end, 1932-1934.
        Plate number, La légende du grand Saint Nicolas, in manuscript: R. L. 11853 & Cie (Rouart Lerolle); corrected in manuscript from R. L. 11839 & Cie.
        Purchased from J & J Lubrano on the Douglas M. Moffat Fund, 2004.
- Isouard, Nicolo, 1775-1818
  - Music
    - Unidentified
      - Unidentified fragment, [1789?]; 1 ms. music fragment ([2] p.); 21 x 26 cm. (Box Folder 387)
        Fragment of unidentified music, holograph, signed.
        Annotated in an unidentified hand: "à l'âge de 14 ans par N. I."
        Purchased from L'autographe on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2004.
- Jeritza, Maria, 1887-
  - Other Papers
    - Photograph of MJ, n.d.; 1 item (1 p.); 14 cm. (Box Folder 296)
      Postcard with a printed reproduction of a photograph, signed.
      Former group number: 40 JERITZA, MARIA
      From the collection of Dr. S. C. G. Watkins.
- Knosp, Gaston, 1874-1942
  - Music
    - Kahirah
      - "El' Kahirah: impressions du Caire / Gaston Knosp", 1912 January 22; [16] p. of ms. music; 36 cm. (Box Oversize Folder 66)
        Music for piano, holograph. Signed at end, 1912 January 22, Brussels, with additional notes about performances, 1912-1913.
        Dedication to Claude Debussy on title page.
- Kreisler, Fritz, 1875-1962
  - Other Papers
    - Photograph of FK, n.d.; 1 item (photograph); 17.4 x 12.3 cm. (Box Folder 297)
      Portrait photograph, signed, 1923.
      Former group number: 41 KREISLER, FRITZ
- Kuhn, Lili
  - Correspondence
    - Letters to Lili Kuhn, 1888-1928, n.d.; 7 items. (Box Folder 298)
      Seven ALS to Lili Kuhn, 1895-193[2?], addressed to Fräulein Lili Koppel, Frau Consul Lili Kuhn, or Direktor Lili Kuhn, from correspondents including German musicians of the 19th and 20th centuries. One letter consists of a quotation of music by an unidentified composer, 1923.
      Former group number: 42 KUHN, LILI
      Gift of Philip Neufeld, 1981.
    - Third party correspondence, 1888-1928, n.d.; 15 items. (Box Folder 299)
      Fifteen ALS to Paul Koppel, Direktor Arno Kuhn, consul in Columbia, and others, from correspondents including Marie Brema, Pelagie Greeff-Andriessen, with a photograph of PGA, Vinzenz Lachner, Hermann Stegemann, and other German musicians of the 19th and 20th centuries.
  - Other Papers
    - Concert programs and autographs, 1896-1928, n.d.; 19 items. (Box Folder 300)
      Fifteen autographs written on printed "Autogramm" cards, most with musical quotations, 1895-1896 and n.d., including Reinhold Becker, Wilhem Kienzl, Max von Schillings, and other German musicians; printed programs for performances by the Quartett Udel, 1896 Mar 9, signed by the performers, August Junkermann, 1896 Jul 8, and the Budapest Quartet, 1928 Dec 9, signed by Emil Hauser, Harry Son, and Joseph Roisman; and a sheet signed by members of the Rosé Quartet, Arnold Rosé, Anton Ruzitska, Paul Fischer, and Anton Walter, 1927 Nov 26.
  - Restricted Fragile
    - Folder 298, n.d.; 1 item. (Box Restricted Fragile Folder 9)
- Lalo, Edouard, 1823-1892
  - Music
    - Roi d'Ys. Ouverture; arr.
      Opera, with libretto by Edouard Blau.
      Composed 1875-1888. First performed 1888. Published in vocal score, 1888.
      - "Le roi d'Ys: ouverture / Edouard Lalo", undated; [7] p. of ms. music; 36 cm. (Box Oversize Folder 67)
        Incomplete arrangement for reed organ, holograph.
        Purchased from Pierre Berès (Hotel Drouot sale, 2004 March 18, lot 49) on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2004.
- Law, Andrew, 1749-1821
  - Other Papers
    - Copyright for Andrew Law's Musical Primer, 1781; 1 item (3 p.); 34 cm. (Box Folder 301)
      Manuscript copy, in an unidentfied hand, of the copyright for the first edition of Andrew Law's Musical Primer, granted by Governor and Company of the State of Connecticut, assembled at Hartford on 1781 Oct 2.
      Followed by a note: "A true copy of record examind by George Wyllys, Secrety."
      Former group number: 43 LAW, ANDREW
      Gift, 1939.
- Lecocq, Charles, 1832-1918
  - Correspondence
    - Unidentified, n.d.; 1 item (4 p.); 16 cm. (Box Folder 302)
      ALS to "Monsieur," a librettist, declining his libretto on the subject of Telemachus.
      Former group number: 44 LECOCQ, CHARLES
  - Music
    - Testament de M. de Crac
      Opera, with libretto by Jules Moinaux.
      First performed 1871; published 1872.
      - "Mr. de Crac", [circa 1871]; 1 ms. score ([circa 100] p.); 28 x 36 cm. (Box Volume 46)
        Score, holograph, with revisions.
- Lefèvre, Marcel
  - Music
    - Robert Macaire. Vocal score
      Former group number: 45 LEFEVRE, MARCEL
      - "Robert Macaire: comédie lyrique bouffe en 3 actes et 4 tableaux / poëme de M. Lefèvre et P. Martinetti; musique de M. Lefèvre", [ca. 1900]; 1 ms. score (2 v.); 34 cm. and smaller. (Box Volume 15-16)
        Vocal score, written in manuscript in an unidentified hand.
        Purchased from Librairie Musicale Ancienne on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund.
- Leigh, Henry S. (Henry Sambrooke), 1837-1883
  - Music
    - Prinz Methusalem. English
      Operetta, with libretto in German by Karl Treumann.
      First performed 1877; published (vocal score) 1877.
      Former group number: 46 LEIGH, HENRY S.
      - "Prince Methusalem", 1880; 1 v. ([43] leaves); 32 cm. (Box Volume 17)
        Autograph manuscript of an English translation of spoken dialogue translated by Henry S. Leigh, British author, dramatist, composer of popular songs, and translator of comic opera libretti.
        Note on t.p. in another hand: "by Henry S. Lee [sic], 1880, J. Strauss, music".
        Leaves numbered as 153 pages, including blank leaves.
        Gift of Philip Neufeld.
- Lejet, Edith
  - Music
    - Pièces brèves
      - "Cinq pièces brèves pour piano / Edith Lejet", [1963?]; 9 p. of ms. music; 37 cm. (Box Oversize Folder 68)
        Music for piano, manuscript, diazo reproduction.
        Date from manuscript annotation in an unidentified hand.
- Leoncavallo, Ruggiero, 1858-1919
  - Correspondence
    - Ferrari, Signor, 1901 Feb 7; 1 item (2 p.); 21 cm. (Box Folder 304)
      ALS referring to production of his opera Zazà.
      Former group number: 47 LEONCAVALLO, RUGGIERO
      Purchased from Lisa Cox (Sotheby's, 2000 May 26, lot 155) on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund.
    - Pirani, n.d.; 1 item (1 p.); 19 cm. (Box Folder 305)
      ALS, with envelope, to his copyist Pirani, concerning titling of instrumental parts.
      Purchased from Lisa Cox (Sotheby's, 1999 Dec 9, lot 152) on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund.
    - Vaucaire, Maurice, [1906]; 1 item (4 p.); 28 cm. (Box Folder 306)
      ALS, Brissago, Switzerland, discussing agreements made by Vaucaire to write libretti for Leoncavallo (Le jeunesse de Figaro) and Giacomo Puccini (Conchita). Leoncavallo also discusses performance of his opera Zazà.
      Purchased from Bernard Quaritch, Ltd. (Sotheby's, London, 2000 Dec 8, lot 111) on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund.
    - [Corradi, E. ?], 1917 May 13; 1 item (2 p.); 24 cm. (Box Folder 303)
      ALS, Viareggio, discussing an unidentified operetta.
      Purchased from William Reese Co. (Swann sale, 2000 Feb 10, lot 135) on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund.
    - Unidentified, [1892]; 1 item (6 p.); 31 cm. (Box Folder 307)
      ALS, Milan, to "Mon cher ami," concerning plans for performances of his operas and discussing Victor Maurel and Giuseppe Verdi.
    - Unidentified, n.d.; 1 item (4 p.); 16 cm. (Box Folder 311)
      ALS to "Cher Monsieur," concerning Leoncavallo's I Medici and his views on Richard Wagner.
      Purchased from Pierre Berès (Drouot-Richelieu sale, Paris, 2000 Nov 29-30, lot 130) on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund.
    - Unidentified, 1895 Jan 24; 1 item (4 p.); 14 x 18 cm. (Box Folder 308)
      ALS to "Chere madame et excellente amie" regarding productions of his operas and problems with his publisher.
      Purchased from Walter R. Benjamin on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund.
    - Unidentified, [ca. 1904]; 1 item (3 p.); 18 cm. (Box Folder 310)
      ALS, in French, to "Chere et bonne amie," requesting a complete Italian translation of Der Roland von Berlin, a novel by Willibald Alexis, for his publisher Edoardo Sonzogno.
    - Unidentified, 1902 Dec 12; 1 item (4 p.); 16 cm. (Box Folder 309)
      ALS to "Cher Monsieur," concerning a social engagement.
  - Music
    - Zazà. De l'aurore quittait
      Opera, with libretto by Leoncavallo,after the play by Pierre Berton and Charles Simon.
      First performed 1900; published 1900; revised by Renzo Bianchi 1947.
      - "De l'aurore quittait", 1904 May 29; 1 ms. vocal score (3 p.); 35 cm. (Box Oversize Folder 27)
        Excerpt from his opera Zazà, signed at Nice, Theatre du Cassino, and inscribed to Marie de Farconnet.
        Text in French; libretto originally in Italian.
        Title from first line of text.
        Purchased from Lisa Cox (Sotheby's, London, 1997 Dec 5, lot 99) on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund.
  - Other Papers
    - "Oblio", n.d.; 1 item (1 p.); 23 cm. (Box Folder 312)
      Poem, holograph, signed.
  - Restricted Fragile
    - Folder 304, 1901; 1 item. (Box Restricted Fragile Folder 10)
- Lind, Jenny, 1820-1887
  - Correspondence
    - Rimmel, W. E., 1847 Jun 10; 1 item (1 p.); 19 cm. (Box Folder 313)
      ALS, Clairville, possibly a facsimile, thanking Rimmel for a bottle of perfume.
      Former group number: 48 LIND, JENNY
      Removed from the W. J. Linton Papers, 1940.
    - Unidentified, n.d.; 1 item (fragment); 7 x 16 cm. mounted on sheet 28 x 22 cm. (Box Folder 314)
      Closing line and signature clipped from an ALS and mounted on sheet.
      Forms part of the Daggett autograph collection.
- Liszt, Franz, 1811-1886
  - Correspondence
    - Landy, Monsieur, 1850 Oct 11; 1 item (4 p.); 21 cm. (Box Folder 315)
      ALS, Weimar, discussing arrival and living arrangements for Liszt and Carolyne de Sayn-Wittgenstein at Bad Eilsen.
      Former group number: 49 LISZT, FRANZ
- Lully, Jean Baptiste, 1632-1687
  - Music
    - Armide
      Opera, with libretto by Philippe Quinault, after Tasso.
      First performed and published in 1686.
      - "Armide: tragedie / par Monsieur de Lully, 1686", [between 1686 and 1702]; 1 ms. score ([358] p.); 40 cm. (Box Volume 40)
        Score, copyist's manuscript with revisions, dated 1702 May 10 at end. Annotated with the inital "L," possibly by Lully, on endpaper.
        Pages numbered 1-138, 147-366.
        Binding: contemporary marbled calf.
        Purchased from James Cummins Bookseller on the Edith and Richard French Fund, 2002.
    - Ballets. Selections
      Former group number: 50 LULLY, JEAN BAPTISTE
      - "Anciens ballets de Mr. de Lully", [16--]; 1 v. of music (303 p.); 20 x 27 cm. (Box Volume 18)
        Autograph manuscript by a contemporary copyist, consisting of music for a treble instrument, possibly a dessus part, from music composed by Lully for various ballets, including ballets and comédies-ballets composed in collaboration with Isaac de Benserade and Molière. A table of contents written by a former owner is laid in.
        Spine title: Anciens ballets dessus.
        Bound in calf with gilt spine, French ca. 1700; unidentified arms on front and back covers.
        Purchased from Arthur Rau, Paris, by Walter L. Pforzheimer. Ex libris Walter L. Pforzheimer, Yale 1935.
        Gift of Walter L. Pforzheimer (Yale 1935).
- Mascagni, Pietro, 1863-1945
  - Correspondence
    - Orsini, Giovanni, 1921-34; 5 items. (Box Folder 316)
      Four ALS and one TLS, with four envelopes, regarding Orsini's legal case; Mascagni's appointment to the academy; Orsini's article on Masacagni's work; and the death of Mascagni's brother.
      Former group number: 52 MASCAGNI, PIETRO
    - Soffredini, Alfredo, 1881 Feb 26; 1 item (3 p.); 27 cm. (Box Folder 317)
      ALS, Livorno, expressing gratitude to his teacher Soffredini, and discussing his cantata In Filanda, for which Soffredini wrote the libretto and conducted the first performance, 1881 Feb 9.
      In Italian. Accompanied by a typescript English translation.
  - Music
    - Il piccolo Marat
      Opera, with libretto by Giovacchino Forzano.
      First performed 1921; published 1921.
      - Fragment from Il piccolo Marat, 1920 January 9; 1 ms. vocal score fragment ([2] p.); 34 cm. (Box Oversize Folder 69)
        Vocal score fragment, holograph. Signed at end, 1920 January 9, Ardenza.
        Purchased from William Reese Co. (Swann sale, 2003 April 3, lot 227) on the Library Associates Fund, 2003.
    - Rantzau. Sol che il sole risplenda
      Opera, with libretto by Guido Menasci and Giovanni Targioni-Tozzetti, based on a play by Émile Erckmann.
      First performed 1893, Florence; published 1892 (vocal score).
      - "Sol che il sole risplenda", 1894 Nov 1-2; 1 ms. score (13 p.); 40 cm. (Box Volume 19)
        Score of the final scene of I Rantzau, with corrections, signed and dated at Milan, 1894 Nov 1. The score varies from the version published in 1892 and apparently is a revision of the scene. Appended is an inscription to Arturo Pirani, Milan, 1894 Nov 2.
        Purchased from Lisa Cox on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 1997.
    - Unidentified
      - Fragment of unidentified vocal music, 1882 February 7; 1 ms. score fragment ([2] p.); 30 cm. (Box Folder 389)
        Holograph score fragment for unaccompanied voices (SSATB), possibly from Alla gioia. Signed at end, 1882 February 7, Livorno.
- Massenet, Jules, 1842-1912
  - Correspondence
    - Bas, Louis, 1907 [i.e. 1908?] Jun 26; 1 item (1 p.); 17 cm. (Box Folder 1)
      Brief ALS, with envelope, thanking his recipient.
      Letter dated 1907; envelope postmarked 1908.
      Former group number: 1 MASSENET, JULES
    - Beulé, Charles-Ernest, 1869 Oct 26; 1 item (1 p.); 21 cm. (Box Folder 2)
      ALS, Paris, asking for support in an opera competition.
    - Bottesini, Giovanni, 1883 Aug 17; 1 item (1 p.); 18 cm. (Box Folder 3)
      From Bottesini: ALS, Naples, asking Massenet for an autograph to benefit victims of the earthquake in Casamicciola.
    - Boucheron, 1899 Apr 3; 1 item (3 p.); 18 cm. (Box Folder 4)
      From "Boucheron": ALS, about a recommmendation for "Soldat Bérerd."
    - Boucheron, Maxime, 1896 Jan 1; 1 item (1 p.); 9 x 12 cm. (Box Folder 5)
      From Boucheron: brief ALS, offering compliments.
    - Bouchet, Francis, n.y. Jan 30; 1 item (4 p.); 19 cm. (Box Folder 6)
      From Bouchet: ALS, Paris, requesting tickets.
      Annotated by Massenet.
    - Bouchor, Maurice, 1890 Jan 1; 1 item (3 p.); 21 cm. (Box Folder 7)
      From Bouchor: ALS, about Bouchor's nomination to the Légion d'honneur.
    - Bouguereau, William Adolphe, 1888-1894; 3 items. (Box Folder 8)
      From Bouguereau: two ALS, Paris, 1888 Sep 30 and 1894 Feb 1, about Clement Fournier, a trombonist; and brief ALS, Paris, 1890 Apr 16, declining a request.
    - Boukay, Maurice, 1912 Jul 14; 1 item (1 p.); 22 cm. (Box Folder 9)
      From Boukay: TLS, Paris, about Émile and Vincent Isola.
    - Brisson, Adolphe, n.y. Aug 29; 1 item (1 p.); 18 cm. (Box Folder 10)
      Brief ALS, thanking his recipient.
    - Brou, marquise de, 1898 Sep 13; 1 item (2 p.); 18 cm. (Box Folder 11)
      ALS, Paris, about his departure for Versailles.
    - Cain, Henri, 1895 Oct 31; 1 item (2 p.); 14 cm. (Box Folder 12)
      ALS about revision of La Navarraise, and referring to Emma Calvé's performance in the opera.
      Carte pneumatique; includes address leaf.
    - Capoul, Victor, 1900 Jun 13; 1 item (1 p.); 14 cm. (Box Folder 13)
      From Capoul: ALS, Paris, about Le Cid.
    - Clairin, Georges, n.d.; 1 item (6 p.); 36 cm. (Box Oversize Folder 1)
      From Clairin: ALS, possibly incomplete, discussing a trip to Nice by Louise and Juliette Massenet, including pencil, ink, and watercolor drawings, with captions and music. Drawings include Louise and Juliette Massenet in Nice, caricatures of Jules Massenet and the Clairin family, and caricatures of Clairin, with music, parodying Charles Gounod's Faust.
    - Claretie, Jules, 1892-1911, n.d.; 63 items. (Box Folder 14-15)
      Sixty-two ALS, 1892-1911 and undated, most about their collaboration on La Navarraise, Amadis, and Thérèse, including additional lines for the libretto of Thérèse; and one ALS to "Madame,"offering congratulations on her performance.
      Gift of Philip M. Neufeld.
    - Colonne, Edouard, 1881-19[02?], n.d.; 9 items. (Box Folder 16)
      From Colonne: nine ALS, most Paris and Berlin, most discussing works by Massenet, including 1ère suite d'orchestre, Esclarmonde, La vierge, Le mage, Werther, and incidential music for Phèdre.
    - Combarieu, J. (Jules), 1909 Sep 18; 1 item (3 p.); 22 cm. (Box Folder 17)
      From Combarieu: ALS, Paris, thanking Massenet for a canon.
    - Comettant, Oscar, 1891 Dec 1; 1 item (1 p.); 16 cm. (Box Folder 18)
      Brief ALS, Paris, arranging a meeting.
    - Comte, Jules, 1912 Aug 18; 1 item (3 p.); 16 cm. (Box Folder 19)
      From Comte: ALS to Louise Massenet, about the death of Jules Massenet.
    - Constant, Benjamin, 1897 Nov 28; 1 item (2 p.); 14 cm. (Box Folder 20)